A missing father. A desperate search. An unforgettable adventure.
Alaska is a family, drama, adventure film directed by Fraser Clarke Heston.
Jake Barnes and his two kids, Sean and Jessie, have
moved to Alaska after his wife died.
He is a former airline pilot now delivering toilet paper across the mountains.
During an emergency delivery in a storm his plane
goes down somewhere in the mountains.
Annoyed that the authorities aren't doing enough, Jessie and Sean set out on an adventure to find their
father with the help of a polar bear which they have saved from a ferocious poacher.
Conflict ensues.
Jessie Barnes, played by Thora Birch.
Sean Barnes, played by Vincent Kartheiser.
Jake Barnes, played by Dirk Benedict.
Charlie, Quincy Air Service, played by Ben Cardinal.
Florence, played by Kristin Lehman.
Trooper Sam Harvey, played by Stephen E. Miller.
Alaska is a 1996 American adventure survival film directed by Fraser
Clarke Heston and produced by Carol Fuchs and Andy Burg.
The story, written by Burg and Scott Myers, centers on two children who
search through the Alaskan wilderness for their lost father.
During their journey, they find a polar bear who
helps lead them to their father.
However, a poacher with a desire to capture the bear follows
close behind the children and the polar bear.
The director's father, Charlton Heston, plays the main antagonist.
The movie was filmed primarily in the Purcell Mountains of
British Columbia in Canada and the city of Vancouver.
The film was a box office bomb, grossing only
$11,829,959 against a $24 million budget.
It received negative reviews upon its release.
The film explores themes of pilot, polar bear, poacher, alaska, airplane crash.
The tone is emotional.